all right so our stakeholder grid this is
part of identify stakeholders and this is
the data representation portion so I will
again reiterate how important it is that
we identify engage all stakeholders
appropriately it's it can mean the
difference between project success and
failure all right so this is important so
this is a way if you have a lot of
stakeholders a way to categorize the
stakeholders all right so a power and
interest grid you could also do power and
influence or impact influence this happens
to be an example of their interest from
low to high and power from low to high so
we will categorize each of our
stakeholders again by their power ability
to use use their authority and then their
interest on their project from low to
high.
So you can see in this top right
quadrant, these are stakeholders
with a lot of power and a
lot of interest in our project.
So we're going to have to manage them
closely.
Keep your friends close, keep your enemies
closer.
If you have powerful stakeholders
who are resistant to the
project, to keep them very
close, manage them very closely.
Over here, these are stakeholders
who have a lot of power,
not a whole bunch of interest
in our project or its outcomes.
So we'll keep them satisfied.
These over here, stakeholders with low
power, low interest, they don't really care.
So we'll monitor them.
We're not going to spend a lot of time on
them.
Whereas these, these stakeholders don't
have a lot of power but they are very
interested in our project so we'll keep
them informed so again we're trying to
figure out to categorize
the stakeholders again try to
narrow them down especially
if you have a lot of stakeholders